Many countless nights passed...
FIRE
Chakra had been dispersed
to those who were unworthy.
WIND
The seal that caused
such deep humiliation...
EARTH
(ゼツ)幾万の夜を数え→
LIGHTNING
has now been shattered.
WATER
本来 持たざる者へと
拡散してしまったチャクラ。
May the infinite moonlight guide you...
Use my body...
長きにわたる屈辱の封印を
解かれし 今→
and become one again!
Awaken, god almighty!
無限の月光に導かれ→
我を依り代に
再び 一つとならん！
Progenitor of chakra!
目覚めよ。
チャクラの祖にして 全能の神！
Thus concludes the tale of revival...
It's chakra!
(ゼツ)復活の物語は
ここに完結する。
(サスケ)チャクラだ。
(サクラ)うわっ！
This is really bad, Sasuke!
This chakra is much stronger
than Ten Tails'!
Stop them before they move!
(マダラ)うわ～！
(ナルト)このままじゃ やべぇぞ サスケ。
これ 十尾どころじゃねえぞ！
チャクラ。
動く前に止める！
Like two moths flying into the flame...
I'm going to absorb
all the chakra out of the two
of you right now.
Damn it!
(ゼツ)火に飛び入る虫 ２匹。
お前らも 今 この場で
チャクラを吸収してやる。
クソッ！
Isn't she...
Isn't she the one Super Gramps
talked about?
Kaguya... Otsutsuki?!
コイツ コイツ…
大じいちゃんが言ってた…。
大筒木カグヤ。
aimaina hyouden koshiraete hitatteru no
I create a vague critical biography and wallow in it
seisei saisai nani o mada matteru no
Generation after generation, time after time,
what are you still waiting for
itsunomanika hitori ni natta
I was all alone before I knew it
tameiki hitotsu haite nageite
Breathed out a single sigh and lamented
jounetsu moyashita ano koro o
Those days of burning passion
shinketsu sosoide torimodosunda
Put your heart and soul into getting them back
en de tsunagareba kono hibi mo
Bind these days with bonds and perhaps
suteru hodo koware tenaidarou
They can be salvaged
ayumi o tomenaide
Don't stop walking forward
kibou o sutenaide
Don't give up hope
douka furimuite
Please look back
dou ka kimiyo
Please, if you would
jin jin kokoro ga itamunara
If the heart throbs with pain
kannen no ori o uchiyaburu nda
Break through the ideology that imprisons you
enen tsukihi wa megurukedo
Time goes around for eternity
suteru ni wa yami ga asaidarou
But the darkness within you is still shallow,
not worth throwing it all away
jounetsu moyashita ano koro o
Those days of burning passion
shinketsu sosoide torimodosu nda
Put your heart and soul into getting them back
ai o wakeaeba kono hibi mo
If we love each other then surely these days will
mouichido kimi o terasudarou
Once again, shine upon you
She of the Beginning
うわっ！
Sasuke!
Sasuke! Naruto!
サスケ！
(サクラ)サスケ君！ ナルト！
The way they are currently,
those two can manage...
But Sakura...
Don't make any careless
moves right now!
《カカシ : 今のあの２人なら大丈夫だ。
These two...
それよりサクラ
今 うかつに動くなよ》
are Hagoromo and Hamura's...
No, rather they're...
Indra and Ashura's...
(カグヤ)こやつら２人
ハゴロモとハムラの…。
いや これが インドラとアシュラか。
So it was Hagoromo
who gave them the jutsu...
Sasuke! Naruto!
Thank goodness!
なら 術を渡したのは ハゴロモか。
Who is she?
And why did Madara
suddenly become her?
《サスケ君 ナルト よかった…。
This chakra is far greater
than Madara's...
誰なの？
なんでマダラが 急にこんな…》
I can't believe such
a person ever existed.
《このチャクラ マダラなど比じゃない。
Hagoromo knew she would appear,
こんなヤツが 存在するとは…》
that's why he entrusted us with—
《ハゴロモは コイツが出てくると
踏んで 俺たちに…》
Obito...
《オビト…》
What are your intentions?
Ninshu...
No, you said shinobi...
It's futile to speak to you about that,
あなたの目的は何だ？
when all you do is just tamper
with chakra,
(カグヤ)忍宗… いや 忍といったか。
without knowing its true meaning.
This place, this land...
is my precious nursery.
チャクラの意味も知らず
もてあそぶ そちらに話しても→
I cannot let it be damaged further.
せんないことだが→
ここは… この地は
わらわの大切な苗床だ。
Let us stop fighting...
Then...
これ以上
傷つけるわけにもいかぬ。
Here that is...
もう戦いは やめにしよう。
えっ？
I shall erase...
You all here...
なら…。
ここではな。
No way!
(カグヤ)ここで
お前らを消すとしようぞ。
Is that lava below?
Is this a genjutsu?
No...
うわ～っ!!
This feels...
different!
Summoning Jutsu!
そんな…。
《下は溶岩… 幻術なのか？
Sasuke! Over there!
いや この感じ… 違う！》
口寄せの術！
サスケ！ あっちだ!!
What're you doing?
Help them, not me!
How did you...?
何してる！ 俺じゃなくて…。
はぁ… はぁ… はぁ…。
Kakashi tied one end of a scroll onto
a kunai and used it like a rope.
どうやって？
For Obito, he just pinned him
to the wall with a kunai, however...
カカシは クナイに
巻物の端を結びつけて→
Way to go, Kakashi Sensei!
ロープ代わりにしたんだ。
Obito...
Sorry for being rough with you...
オビトは クナイで刺し止めただけだが。
Oh!
さすが カカシ先生！
《オビト… 手荒くなって すまない》
It wasn't a genjutsu, after all...
あっ…。
Don't tell me...
She summoned a different dimension?
やはり 幻術じゃなかったね。
《まさか…。
別空間を口寄せした
とでもいうのか？》
Eyes forward, Naruto.
Naruto...
I'm going to be frank with you...
前を見ろ ナルト。
This world will come to an end
if either one of us dies.
ナルト お前に ここで
はっきり言っておく。
Only your Six Paths Power
of the Light Style
and my Six Paths Power
of the Shadow Style,
俺とお前
どちらか一方が死んだとしても→
can seal away that being
in front of us.
この世は終わりだ。
お前の六道の陽の力と→
If we don't succeed,
mankind will perish.
俺の陰の力だけが
目の前のあれを封印できる。
We can't afford to die,
no matter what...
When the Infinite Tsukuyomi
was launched...
そうできなければ
人類は滅亡することになる。
Kakashi and Sakura just happened
to be near you...
That's just how it is.
俺たちは何があっても
死ぬわけにはいかん。
You understand
what that means, right?
無限月読のとき カカシとサクラは
たまたま お前の近くにいた。
そういうことだ。
この意味 わかるな…。
I know.
I get what you're saying
and I know that you're right.
But... this is also a situation when
your body just moves on its own...
わかってんよ。
お前の言ってることも
わかってるつもりだ。
Like that time on the bridge.
けど… こういうときは
体が勝手に動いちまうもんだろ。
Sasuke, you...!
橋でのとき…。
Why did you protect me?
((サスケ お前…。
What's with that look? Loser...
なんで…。
《俺をかばって…》
Why did you—?!
For me—?
うっ… なんて顔してやがんだよ。
You should have just minded
your own business!
How should I know?
このウスラトンカチ。
なんで 俺なんか…。
余計なお世話だ！
知るかよ そんなこと…。
My body just moved on its own...
(体が勝手に動いちまったんだよ…
バカ…))
Well, never mind.
I know that you get
what I mean, Sasuke.
まあ いいや。
この意味
お前ならわかるよな？ サスケ。
Sasuke's right.
Back then...
Maybe Sasuke acted subconsciously...
《サスケ君の言うとおり…。
あのとき もしかしたら
サスケ君は 無意識に…》
Even so...
Thank you... Naruto.
《でも… ありがとう ナルト》
Damn it!
あっ… しまった！
うわっ！
Now's our chance!
クソッ！
Byakugan!
Damn it! My hawk's Chakra Points
have been hit!
今のうちに！
《白眼！ しまった!?
タカの点穴をつかれた！》
This calls for Susano'o!
うっ うわっ！
《こうなったら 須佐能乎で！》
Madara's rods are...
I can finally move...
Now if...
If I head to the spot where
I sensed that massive chakra...
《柱間 : マダラの棒が…》
I might learn something.
やっと動ける。 これで あの…。
《扉間 : 強大なチャクラを
感知した場所まで行ってみれば→
But... the chakra
suddenly dissipated.
何かわかるかもしれぬ》
FOURTH HOKAGE
They've disappeared...
Did they defeat Madara?
《ヒルゼン : だが…
急にチャクラが消えた》
I've got to get to Naruto...
just one more time...
(ミナト)消えた。 マダラを倒したのか？
Naruto, you—?!
Huh?
《もう一度 ナルトのところへ…》
You can levitate?
(カカシ)ナルト お前…。
That's right...
Madara, when he was enhanced
by Six Paths' chakra, also levitated...
えっ？
(カカシ)浮けるのか？
え？ あっ！
《確かに 六道のチャクラを得た
マダラも浮いてたしな…》
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
影分身の術！
Take care of Sakura and Kakashi Sensei.
Six Paths' Chakra...
You act triumphantly just because
you have a special accoutrement.
サクラちゃんとカカシ先生を頼む。
However...
No matter what kind of chakra...
六道のチャクラ。
All chakra belongs to me
and me alone.
特別な遊具をもらい得意顔か。
だがの…
どのようなチャクラであろうとも→
チャクラとは わらわ 唯一のもの。
Once more...
... I shall reunify all chakra!
もう一度→
チャクラをひとつにする！
うぉ～っ！
Sasuke! Now!
《サスケ 今だ！》
Sasuke!
Damn it! I can't stop!
サスケ！
《クソッ 止まんねえ！》
Sasuke!
Even Susano'o doesn't work.
ぐわっ！
サスケ！
須佐能乎すら効かない。
Let's get Obito while
we still have the chance.
I forgot that you could use
Teleportation-like jutsu now.
今のうちに オビトを。
You had me worried there!
It's like this foothold.
お前が 瞬身の術みてぇなの
使えるようになってたの→
We've both benefitted
from Six Paths' power.
忘れてたぜ。
But having received it is meaningless
unless we seal her away.
心配させやがって。
この足場のやつにしろ→
Yeah!
お互い六道仙人の力の恩恵だ。
だが ヤツを封印しなければ
それを受けた意味がない。
おう！
My children, with whom
I shared my chakra...
《カグヤ : チャクラをわけた我が子たち》
I can't move...
Now... come to your mother...
She's taking... our chakra, Sasuke!
《動けねえ》
《さぁ 母のもとへ》
Kaguya seems to see
her two children...
when she looks at the two of you.
チャクラ… 取られてんぞ サスケ！
Isn't that sweet?
(ゼツ)カグヤは お前たち２人を見て→
She, who was sealed away
by her own children.
Such a poor, pitiable mother...
我が子２人を思い出したようだ。
Why'd Six Paths Super Gramps
seal away his own mom?
しおらしいだろ？
我が子に封印されたカグヤ
かわいそうな母親だ。
I thought he sealed away Ten Tails...
It appears you have the wrong idea...
なんで 六道の大じいちゃんが
母ちゃんを…。
Just who and what are you,
Black Zetsu?
封印されたのは 十尾だろ。
I am Kaguya's child.
何か勘違いを
しているようだな。
What?!
His aura seems different,
all of a sudden...
黒ゼツ お前は何者だ？
I recorded everything that happened
while Mother was gone.
俺は カグヤの子供だ。
And molded it as well.
なんだと？
《コイツ 雰囲気が変わった》
The tale of shinobi...
is the tale of restoring Mother.
(ゼツ)母のいない間の
すべてを記録し→
Huh?! What're you talking about?!
その間を俺が作った。
What do you mean?
忍の物語は
母が復活するための物語だ。
Since you know Mother's name,
you must have met Hagoromo.
はぁ!? 何言ってんだ。
I knew that it was possible, depending on
the power of the reincarnates.
どういうことだってばよ？
(ゼツ)母の名を
知っているということは→
As well as receiving the power
to seal away Mother...
ハゴロモに会ったということだな。
転生者の力次第では
会うことができると知っている。
But we're gonna seal away
the Ten Tails!
It's rare to see the reincarnates
of Indra and Ashura
母を封印するために
力を渡すことも。
cooperating this closely.
You two know nothing.
封印すんのは十尾だ。
Let me tell you her tale while
I suck out all of your chakra.
ここまで協力する
インドラとアシュラの転生者は珍しい。
Like I told you earlier...
Mother was sealed away previously
by her own children.
何も知らない お前らに→
チャクラを吸い取る間
その物語を聞かせてやろう。
Apparently, it was an extremely
powerful seal...
さっきも言ったな。
母は かつて我が子の手で
封印されたと。
The jutsu transformed Ten Tails into
a Catastrophic Planetary
Devastation core...
それは それは
強力な封印だったそうだ。
... and turned it into the moon.
But just before the seal took hold,
she gave birth to me.
十尾自身を
地爆天星の核へと変える術。
In order that she could
one day be restored.
それによって 十尾は月となった。
I shall now show you two
all of that...
だが 封印の寸前で
俺が産み落とされた。
I don't have any candy,
but the puppet show is about to begin.
母がいつか復活するために。
お前たちに見せてやる。
飴玉はないが 紙芝居の始まりだ。
kaze ga fui te iku
The wind is blowing
yoru o mata yorokete aruku
I stagger through the night
butsukatte koron de shippai bakkashite
Colliding, falling, and failing
make sou ni naru kedo
I'm always about to lose
warawaretatte ii yo kanarazu umaku iku sa
Go ahead and laugh, I'll figure out a way
gomen ne datte ieru
I'm even willing to say I'm sorry
nakitai nakitai nakitai kurai ni
Until we feel like crying and crying
kirei na tsuki no shita uta o utaou
Let's sing a song under the pretty moonlight
donna ni kuradanai sekai datte ii yo
It doesn't matter how awful the world is
setsunai setsunai rarabai kurai ni
Like a sad, sad lullaby
mune ga kurushikute mo hecchara na no sa
even if it hurts inside, it won't bother us
naki sou naki sou naki sou na hodo
Until we're about to cry and cry
yasashii uta datte arun dakara
There will always be a gentle song
Are you saying that she came
from the heavens?
Yes, this woman appeared in the spot
where the light had fallen...
What is your name?
Answer him!
The man standing before you
is the King of the Land of Sou,
Lord Tenji!
My name is...
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"Kaguya Otsutsuki"
The ones who protect the Chakra Fruit—!